#### Contact

40408106 (Mobile) a.austvoll@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/andre-austvoll (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

User Experience (UX) Video Production Product Management

### Languages

English (Full Professional)
German (Limited Working)
Norwegian (Native or Bilingual)

# André Austvoll

Immersive Media Consultant & UX Designer Oslo

### Summary

I enjoy analyzing problems and designing solutions to real world challenges. My experience includes work in immersive media, including virtual and augmented reality, as well as video streaming and consulting.

My aim is to be a team player who integrates UX, business understanding and design skills to provide high quality products and services for clients.

### My interests:

- User experience design
- Virtual and augmented reality
- Video streaming solutions

I started my professional career in contemporary dance and choreography, where I learned about working within restrains of budgets, deadlines and international teamwork while touring the globe. As I moved into video production I was involved in the entire creative process from workshop ideation, scripting, previsualisation, storyboarding, scheduling, shooting, editing and designing interfaces for media consumption.

As a video consultant for Canon and currently at Videoutstyr Norge AS, my main focus has been on evaluating user needs and experiences for professional video equipment. I enjoy figuring out my clients requirements and supporting them in buying the appropriate equipment, installation and troubleshooting.

## Experience

Oslo Area, Norway

Videoutstyr Norge AS Video Solutions Specialist & UX Designer September 2011 - Present (9 years 9 months) I have advised on a large number of video, immersive media and communications projects, as well as improved UX on in-house services and webshop. My responsibilities have included marketing, sales and technical support for professional video, 360 cameras and virtual reality equipment. Projects have included supporting clients in broadcast and video production, education, industry, medical and law enforcement.

Since 2017 I have been product manager for Virtual Reality and 360 video hardware and software. One of my achievements was being part of developing a 360 underwater surveillance solution for maritime industries.

Pointmedia User Experience Designer April 2021 - April 2021 (1 month) Oslo, Norway

The VROffice is a remote collaboration service offering virtual reality office space. The 3D space has a number of possible interactions, tools and fucntionality that required user testing. I was involved in user experience inspection of multiple virtual rooms, describing issues and suggesting improvements.

#### Microdance

Videoproduction, Choreography and Dance September 2000 - September 2011 (11 years 1 month) Brazil, China, Finland, Norway, Poland, Russia, Slovenia, England, USA

brazii, China, Finiano, Norway, Polano, Russia, Siovenia, Englano, OSA

I started and ran my own business, working as a dancer, instructor, choreographer, researcher and video producer. In these fields I have managed projects and taken responsibility for art direction, planning, budgeting, executing projects and evaluating team efforts.

Working in the creative field has refined my ability to resolve objectives on time and within financial requirements, while completing projects to a high standard.

Canon Norge as
Marketing & Customer Relations
September 2009 - March 2011 (1 year 7 months)
Norway

Customer and dealer contact across Norway. Marketing of Canon cameras and photographic printers. Participation in promotion events. On-site follow-up of resellers around mid and south Norway.

Product management, field demonstrations, documentation of shop displays and acquiring user feedback.

As a video consultant for Canon my main focus has been on evaluating user needs and experiences for professional video equipment. I enjoy figuring out my clients requirements and supporting them in buying the appropriate equipment, installation and troubleshooting.

### Education

CareerFoundry

Certificate, UX Design Immersion · (2020 - 2021)

Oslo and Akershus University College

Diploma, Process facilitation & innovation · (2008 - 2008)

University of Surrey

Master of Arts (MA), Somatic studies & Laban movement analysis · (2003 - 2005)

**Trinity Laban** 

Bachelor of Arts (BA), Dance Theatre · (1997 - 2000)